主席。
hereinafter referred to as subject OFCs。
investment， and advisory services.
，作為其他相關專業服務。
成員們，的法案委員會一般支持該法案。
我 wish to make a report on the work of the Bills Committee.
我會focus on the major issues considered by the Bills Committee.
In my capacity as chairman of the Bills Committee on the Income Revenue Amendment Bill, Number Four.
按照議事規則，二讀辯論終止待續，條例草案交由內部委員會處理。
and thereby, generating demand for local asset management.
and foster the further development of Hong Kong's financial services industry as a whole.
this will help strengthen Hong Kong's position as an international asset management centre.
條例草案委員會主席梁繼昌議員就委員會報告向本會發言。梁繼昌議員。
本會恢復二零一七年税務修訂第四號條例草案嘅二讀辯論。
The objective of the bill is to amend the inland revenue ordinance to extend profits tax exemption to onshore privately offered open-ended fund companies.
按委員會的建議，建議政府應考慮在適當的時間內，就本港的税務安排作出適當的調整。
precedent。
and lastly.
在course of deliberations.
所以，為防止 abuses of the tax exemption。
by repackaging businesses as subject OFCs.
firstly, the subject OFC must be a resident person.
設出的criteria， for determining whether an OFC is NCH。
transactions of the subject OFC must be carried out or arranged by a qualified person.
委員會已審查，among other issues，the conditions for profits tax exemption。
The bill proposes certain conditions to be met by a subject OFC for profits tax exemption.
第二，ly，the subject OFC must be non-closely held，that is the NCH condition。
第三ly，the subject OFC must invest in permissible asset classes specified by the Securities and Futures Commission.
regarding the definition of qualified investor under the proposed new Section 20A, subsection six.
anti-avoidance measures and the financial and economic implications of the extension of profits tax exemption to the subject OFCs.
The proposed new section 20A(i) sets out the requirements to be met by a subject OFC to be regarded as NCH, and the proposed new schedule 16B.
委員會指出，NCH條款旨在確保申請税收豁免的受惠公司不是由少數個別人士或合資格投資者所擁有。
and a reasonably large size to dump missile in Hong Kong.
將 fall within the definition of qualified investors.
carried out or arranged by a qualified person in Hong Kong.
with a view to attracting funds with a larger number of investors.
The scope of permissible asset classes were largely aligned with that of type 9 asset management.
regulated activity as specified in the Securities and Futures Amendment Ordinance Two Hundred and One Six.
and may consider adjusting the NCH condition, as the market circumstances may warrant.
委員會指出，根據擬議的新第20A節第3小節。
Being a type of institutional investor, which commonly has a larger number of underlying investors.
一10%的 minimise limit is proposed under the bill for allowing a subject OFC to invest in non-permissible asset classes.
委員會已問過行政處
If such limit is exceeded, all profits of the OFC will be tainted and become wholly chargeable to profits tax.
委員會指出，定義證券在擬議的新《規則十六A》中，是從《證券及期貨條例》中引述的。
法案委員會已註意，並未提出任何反對意見，對行政總署提出的修訂，以釐清有關索菲亞資產基金的定義。
A subject OFCs can be eligible for profits tax exemption in respect of profits derived from transactions in permissible asset classes, as prescribed in the proposed new Schedule 16A.
行政會已建議，將會審視擬議的股息税豁免，對提升香港作為基金 domiciliation 位所的競爭力有無幫助，於適當時機。
with the proposed amendments.
on this differential tax treatment.
And miss other requirements in the bill.
會被允許獲準税額豁免於其所有收益。
There is also a concern about a loophole of tax leakage.
to address the above ringfencing concern and plug the loophole.
as such, the tax-exempted profits of the OFCs will not be tainted.
要移除10%的minimums rule，，以及染指條款。
The administration has proposed to amend the proposed section 20A H in the bill.
A sub J O F C， as long as it has been registered with the Securities and Futures Commission.
作為such， a subject OFC may invest in securities of overseas private companies without a limit.
但係，subject to the 10% de minimis limit， in respect of investment in securities of local private companies。
Enhance includes shares or debentures of overseas private companies, but not those of local private companies.
since a subject OFC can invest in securities of overseas companies, which can in turn own assets in Hong Kong.
provided that it does not carry on direct trading or a direct business undertaken in Hong Kong, involving assets of a non-schedule 16A class, and it does not invest specify types of private companies.
the bills committee has raised concern about this tax feature being considered as ring fencing and hence a harmful tax practice under the base erosion and profit shifting package of the organisation for economic cooperation and development.
the bills committee supports the amendments proposed by the administration.
pursuant to the proposed new section 28H, subsection 1.
given that the deeming provisions are only applicable to residents.
profits in respect of the trading profits earned by the OFC.
該法案 contains deeming provisions as set out in the proposed new section 28K.
also， to cater for the actual operation circumstances that an OFC may encounter。
主席，委員會也檢討了法案中提出的反避税措施。
Safe harbour rules are introduced and set out in the proposed new section 20A H, A J, sorry.
thereby ensuring that a subject OFC is non-closely held continuously throughout the life of the fund.
There is also an express provision in the proposed new section 28J subsection 3.
A subject OFC is required to satisfy the NCH condition at all times after the date on which an OFC missed the NCH condition.
Yet a subject OFC is allowed a maximum 24 months after the date on which it accepted as first investor for meeting the condition.
Further, to prevent possible abuse or round tripping by a resident person disguising as a subject of C to take advantage of the proposed tax exemption.
議事委員會已提出擔憂，就是否這個特徵會被視為從國內市場進行買賣，從而是一項有害的税務做法。
to ensure that consideration or remuneration received by a person for providing investment services directly or indirectly for the OFC in the course of a trade or business carried in Hong Kong will be chargeable to profits tax.
Indeed.
on this.
exempt from profits tax under our current taxation regime.
Yet, onshore privately offered funds are still subject to profits tax.
The following part of the speech carries my personal comments on the bill.
and instead may distribute out of capital subject to insolvency and disclosure requirements.
The administration has explained that the deeming provisions should not should be aimed at residents.
also，the OFCs will not be bound by restrictions on distribution of capital application to conventional companies.
This bill will remove this distinction for fund domiciliation and management in Hong Kong.
An OFC is a collective investment scheme, with variable capital set up in the form of a company, but with flexibility.
行政是持觀點，提出的税制係符合最新國際標準。
主席，法案委員會支持行政總署提出的修訂，不會提出任何修訂法案。
In view that non-residents generally may not be subject to Hong Kong tax under a double tax agreement, in the absence of a permanent establishment.
To create and cancel shares for investor subscription and redemption in the funds, which is currently not enjoined by conventional companies.
The objective of the bill is to amend the inland revenue ordinance in order to extend profits tax exemption to onshore, privately offered, open-ended fund companies.
pursuant to this section, a resident person who alone or jointly with his associates holds direct and/or indirect beneficial interest of 30% or more in a tax-exempt OFC or sub-fund will be deemed to have derived assessable.
一subject of these。
And miss other requirements of the bill.
with the proposed additional amendments.
所以，Madam President， why we should support this bill?
The proposal to grant profits tax exemption.
involving access of a non-scheduled 16A class.
它並未投資指定類型的私營公司。
as such, the tax-exempt profits of the overseas will not be tainted.
會被允許 enjoin 税 exempton on all of his profits.
as long as it has been registered with the Security and Futures Commission.
to the subject of C's would help enhance Hong Kong's competitiveness.
在 addition to address the ring fencing concerns and plug a currently existing loophole.
provided it does not carry on direct trading, or direct business undertaking in Hong Kong.
mainly will deter any tax avoidance scheme being used as a result of the introduction of the bill.
The bill proposes certain conditions to be met by its subject OFCs for profit tax exemption, which I will not repeat, and these conditions.
The administration has proposed to amend the proposed section 28H in the bill to move to remove the 10% de minimis rule, as well as the tainting provisions.
The bill levels the playing field for onshore and offshore OFCs as publicly offered funds, whether their central management of control is exercised in or outside Hong Kong, authorised by the SFC, and offshore funds, whether publicly or privately offered, are already.
Indeed.
私營公司assets。
其他則本地不動產，應該持有超過三年。
And，at，the，Bill's，committee，stage，held，on，the，20th，July。
This will certainly help strengthen Hong Kong's position as an international asset management centre.
such a minimum holding period is set to reduce the risk of tax abuse by onshore entities engaging in speculative activities.
2017，last year，I pointed out while the OFCs were not permitted to invest in shares of local private companies.
我 glad that the administration has taken these concerns into consideration and have proposed the corresponding CSA in the bill.
他們被允許投資於海外的私營公司，which could own assets in Hong Kong.
In respect of the domiciliation of privately held OFCs and thereby generating demand for local asset management and a lot of business activities.
And now we have this OFC legislation to provide a suitable environment to enhance Hong Kong as an asset management centre.
作為 consequence of my enquiry, the administration has proposed a committee stage amendment, which would allow OFCs to enjoy profits tax exemption on its investment in private companies, whether local or overseas.
在過去兩年，我們見到很多税收優惠立法，例如香港成為一個企業財務管理中心。我們見到立法來鼓勵機場租賃制度。
我進一步探問，是否這可能引致税漏？即係交易資產課税於profits tax，喺出售時可能成為課税資產，如果出售透過OFC，即係賣股東股份的海外私人公司，持有該交易資產。
provided that number one, these invested private companies do not hold directly or indirectly more than 10% of the assets and local immovable property, and if a subject OFC has a controlling interest in an invested private company, 50% or more of
現在，行政也重複、重複地陳述，基金創建活動，由税 exemption，會驅動對專業服務的需求，例如基金管理及投資顧問，以及法律、會計、行政及其他輔助服務。
give.
now we have yet to receive.
data up-to-date data on how these
另一個點，which I would urge the government to do.
If there is no economic impact, what's the point of doing this legislation?
And in addition to sales and marketing activities.
Of course, we can implement many, many, many more.
Rules or new legislation could be conducive to our economy.
貿易、on our economy、on our professional services、on our fund management industry。
Without ascertaining the economic effect, we cannot afford to have more and more of these legislations because merely.
What is the point of having this legislation on your rulebook if nobody from outside Hong Kong would have known the existence of these schemes?
this kind of legislation，claiming that it is beneficial to the economy，claiming that it is beneficial to the fund industry，claiming that it is beneficial to the professional services。
因此，因此，我會敦促政府，於定期基礎，實施每項税法，提供這些特別獎勵。
And perhaps, with the help and assistance, or in conjunction, of a statutory body or an advisory body, for example, the Financial Services Development Council, is to promote these schemes.
If we do not do that, we will at the end of the day just copying many many other incentive schemes which have been you know adopted in our neighbour jurisdictions like Singapore or even mainland.
The Financial Affairs Panel of this legislature a up to date report of how these legislation have benefited the economy as a whole. I mean, these reports should not be done too frequently. Maybe you can provide us with an annual update of the impact of these legis.
And.
陳振英議員。
我會 like to have a figure on that.
would end up in the rule books, would gather dust.
Without these publicity, all these legislations.
And in five years' time, in ten years' time, when we pull this legislation to have a look again.
嘅法律框架，預期咧亦都喺今年咧實施開放式基金型公司嘅制度啦。
even if they knew of these the existence of these schemes, if no one is there to explain.
Madam President, I will urge my fellow honourable members across the legislature to support the second and third reading of the bill. Thank you.
For example, can you tell me how many companies have been making use of Islamic fund financing, the Islamic bond regime, to issue Islamic bonds in Hong Kong in the past five years?
And I'm waiting for that. And I will urge the government to do two things: one, to assess the economic impact of this legislation; and two, to step up the publicity of these incentive regime.
咁可以培養咧香港自身製造基金嘅能力。不過咧，現存嘅税務安排咧，只有離岸開放式基金先享有利得税豁免，難免咧就窒礙咗香港基金業嘅發展。
公司必須要係非集中擁有啦，必須主要投資喺證監會定定嘅可投資資產嘅類別啦，但係就容許佢哋有一定程度，即係十個percent嘅豁免門檻。而交易咧，亦都必須透過合資格人士進行，或者由合資格嘅人士安排進行等等啦。
到這些潛在投資者、潛在資金，which want to locate in Hong Kong， 什麼係啲複雜性？呢啲立法，我們可以幫佢哋定位啲基金業務喺香港，我們可以幫佢哋定位啲銷售、marketing人到香港。
都係主席。
黃定光議員。
削弱我哋嘅競爭優勢。
個基地，本人啊，僅此陳辭，多謝代主席。
本人僅代表民建聯咧，誒表達對本條例草案嘅立場同埋意見。
當然咧，香港作為一個國際城市，時時刻刻都要緊隨國際社會嘅變更同埋修訂我哋金融經濟嘅法規。
我喺審議草案期間咧，提出咗兩項意見嘅。第一，我希望政府咧日後能夠適時檢討擁有權條件下邊嘅持有權規定。
亦都好高興咧，見到政府咧因應我哋委員喺法案委員會上邊嘅意見，而作出咗必要嘅一啲修改，例如咧對合資格投資者嘅定義咧進行清晰化。
咁修例嘅好處咧，我相信頭先法案委員會主席已經詳細介紹，我就唔再重複啦。我作為草案委員會嘅其中一個成員咧，我係支持通過呢條税例修訂嘅。
咁可以吸引咧更多較具規模嘅基金咧嚟到香港註冊，目標就係將香港咧定位為一個高質嘅基金匯集地，創造更多高端嘅就業機會，成為咧香港金融發展上另外一個新嘅亮點。
代主席，作為一個國際金融中心咧，除咗傳統嘅銀行、證券、保險等等行業之外咧，資產管理業務咧，亦都係必須要積極發展嘅方向。咁特區政府喺二零一六年年中咧已經着手製定開放式基金型公司結構嘅。
呢一條二零一七年税務修訂第四號條例草案，佢嘅宗旨就係修例啦，明確在案嘅開放式基金公司喺符合咗幾項特定嘅條件之後咧，即刻可以獲得利得税嘅豁免嘅，包括咧公司必須要係居港者啦。
立法會咧，亦都經常喺呢度咧審議相關嘅修訂法例。而香港咧過往賴以成功嘅因素咧，就係主動積極與時並進。目前咧，而家其他好多主要嘅基金管合區，例如英國、新加坡，佢哋都大力推動緊佢嘅在岸基金業嘅發展。
所以咧，我想再一次喺呢度提示下特區政府，需要咧主動制定一個時間表去檢討咧持有權呢個規定，唔好咧淨係做一個追隨者，等到其他地區做好曬啦，我哋先至去改例提交嚟立法會審批，噉樣咧只會上。
第二方面咧，我喺委員會上亦都要求政府咧，考慮為呢一類嘅公司咧發出居民身份證明書，令到呢啲公司喺已經同香港簽訂咗全面避免雙重課税協定嘅其他税務管轄區開展業務嗰時咧，可以獲得税。
當時政府當局嘅回覆就話，經合組織咧，正係因應打擊侵蝕税基同埋轉移利潤嘅措施咧，制定緊有關投資工具嘅税務條例待遇嘅立場。政府咧就會留意住呢啲相關國際做法，確保咧，如果一旦真係決定。
無嘅優惠。
因此，當局起條例草案。
喺在岸嘅開放式基金型公司。
民建聯咧係對此表示支持同埋肯定嘅。
推動香港基金註冊同埋管理業務嘅發展。
當中包括設立非集中擁有嘅規定。
鞏固同埋進一步推動香港作為國際金融中心嘅地位。
由於目前香港並冇任何以私人形式發售。
以及限制有關投資者對基金持股嘅比例等等。
本條例草案主要係落實二零一七一八年度財政預算案裡面提出嘅。
從而咧，係吸引私人形式發售嘅開放式基金型公司喺香港註冊。
誒嘅定定嘅過程裡面咧，係設立咗有啲條件，防止有關税務豁免咧係遭到濫用嘅。
將利得税豁免範圍擴大至以私人形式發售嘅在岸開放式基金型嘅公司嘅建議。
當然，呢一啲私人形式發售嘅在岸基金開放誒，在岸開放式嘅基金，投資者咧係會比較少嘅。
規定有關基金嘅最少要有幾多名投資者，有關嘅投資者最少要投資幾多金額？
可能會出現有一啲人或者有啲公司利用私人形式發售嘅在岸基金結構呢，將應課税嘅利潤轉為無需課税嘅收入，以作出避税嘅行為。
因此，呢一啲私人形式發售嘅在岸開放式基金提供嘅税務優惠咧，就可以促又可以有助促進香港基金業同埋財資市場嘅發展。
畀呢啲税務居民身份證嘅話咧，可以符合國際慣例。噉我希望咧，當經合組織嘅立場一旦清晰之後咧，政府能夠盡快跟進呢件事，吸引更多咧具跨國業務嘅基金公司咧，樂於選擇香港作為佢哋嘅基金開拓業務。
嘅目的。
因此喺審議期間咧。
裡面提出非集中擁有嘅規定啦。
而每一名投資者最少嘅投資金額咧，係需要兩億。
規定每一名每一個以私人誒形式發售誒嘅。
大部分嘅委員都關注呢啲税務豁免條件嘅規定。
最低要求咧就提高到十名嘅投資者啦，而每一名投資者金額咧亦都係最少為兩億。
在岸開放式基金咧，係需要有幾多個投資者？每一個投資者最少投資金額呢啲噉嘅門檻。
而當局最後尾喺條例草案提出修訂案中咧，亦都集中咗有關税務豁免條件呢啲規定嘅。
並且啊，要求基金必須把將百分之九十嘅資產總值投資喺證監會指定嘅受規管嘅投資活動裏面。
若果有關基金公司冇任何嘅合格合資格嘅投資者嘅話咧，有關基金公司嘅投資者數目，
然而，為咗比條例草案更加靈活性咧，條例草案中對於非集中擁有嘅規定，亦都作出有啲彈性。
由於本條例草案誒最終是否成功咧，係取決於本條例草案裡面税務豁免條件規定係唔係有效同埋可行。
若果有關私人形式發售嘅在岸開放式基金公司具有一名或者多於一名嘅合格投資者呢？有關基金公司嘅投資者數目嘅最低要求係為五名。
呢一啲税務豁免嘅規定，既可以避免有人利用本條例嘅誒法律漏洞，從事避税嘅舉動，損害我哋特區政府嘅税收穩定，亦都可以確保條例嘅以達到原有政策。
首先，為咗避免有啲人或者有啲公司將現時應要課税嘅收入包裝為私人形式發售嘅在岸開放基金、開放式嘅基金進行規避誒納誒繳税，所以咧，當局喺本條例草案。
主席。
最終。
再者。
政府實體等等。
資格投資者裏面加入咗主權財富基金。
此外啊，委員會喺審議有關基金公司可投資項目嘅時候呢？
呢一啲機構本身係根據現時嘅税務條例咧，都係具有免税嘅優惠嘅。
但唔能夠投資香港本土未上市嘅私人公司股票同埋佢嘅債權證。
亦都發現，根據可投資項目中可以包括海外未上市嘅私人公司股票同埋債權證。
當局係有為咗堵塞技術性嘅逃税漏洞咧，以及避免引起一啲歧視性税務待遇嘅質疑。
用以透過成立私人形式發售在岸開放式基金公司逃税嘅機會咧，係唔大嘅。
有關嘅税務待遇咧嘅差異，可能會畀國際社會認為係一項具有損害性嘅措呢個税務措施。
當局係提出咗修訂案，取消咗有關基金公司不可有超過百分之十嘅投資額投資香港本土未上市公司嘅規定。
呢個亦都可能使有關嘅基金公司可以投資喺海外嘅私人公司證券，而呢啲海外私人公司喺香港擁有資產，從而咧係造成漏洞，導致漏税嘅問題。
當局喺非集中擁有規定裏面提出有合資格嘅投資者同埋冇合資格嘅投資者嘅區別咧，主要喺合資格嘅投資者為非牟利成立嘅機構，好似退休基金啦，向公眾發售嘅基金同埋正。
然而喺委員會審議期間，當局發現有關合資格投資者嘅定義中並未包括咗主權財富基金。為咗畀有關嘅定義更加全面咧，當局係提出咗修訂案喺合。
同時咧，亦都。
嘅開放式基金型嘅公司。
歧視性税務待遇嘅質疑。
會審議嘅階段，動議修正案。
總體嚟講，民建聯認為。
有冇其他議員想發言？
支持以及對條例草案提出嘅意見。
如果冇，我現在請財經事務及庫務局局長答辯，之後辯論即告結束，局長。
需要持有最少百分之五十嘅資產，當中不包括香港嘅物業，超過三年。
如果有關基金公司對該等私人公司擁有嘅控制權，該等私人公司。
但係有關基金公司嘅投資，本地及海外私人公司擁有嘅香港物業不得超過資產百分之十。
冇損害到本條例草案嘅功效，民建聯對此係表示認同嘅。本人僅此陳詞，代表民建聯支持本條例草案同埋佢修訂案。
為咗避免條例草案被國際社會視為係具損害性嘅税務安排，以及堵塞技術性嘅逃税流動，我哋提交咗若干嘅修正案。呢啲修正案得到法案委員會嘅支持，我會喺全體委員。
呢啲修訂案係有助完成完善有關呢個條例草案嘅，堵塞咗有關技術漏洞，以及避免咗引起國際社會對本條例草案可能會招致嘅誒。
德税嘅撥面。
而避免繳税。
標並不一致。
由於基金經理喺選擇基金註冊地嘅時候，會考慮到嗰該地區嘅税務待遇。
呢一個係能夠確保公司會喺香港進行大部分嘅活動，並且聘用本地投資經理，促進香港經濟發展。
條件係第一，公司必須係居港者，並且喺香港進行中央管理同埋控制。換言之，公司必須係在岸。
第二，公司必須喺證監會註冊並符合所有相關法規，包括證監會通過開放式基金型公司守則所定嘅要求。
正常縮減嘅活動，或者暫時且冇法控制嘅情況之下，獲準喺未能符合非集中擁有條件嘅情況之下，繼續享有税務豁免。
因此，我哋需要修訂税務條例，讓以私人形式發售嘅在岸嘅開放式基金型公司同離岸嘅同類基金，同樣係享有利得税嘅豁免。
因此，我有必要為開放式基金型嘅公司提供有利嘅營商環境。根據現行嘅税制，不同嘅基金所享有嘅待遇並不相同。當中離岸同埋向公眾發售嘅基金係可以享有利得税嘅豁免。
以及第四公司嘅交易必須係透過根據證券及期貨條例持牌或者註冊以進行第九類資產管理受規管活動嘅法團或者認可嘅金融機構，在香港進行或者安排嘅進行嘅。
代主席，我感謝法案委員會主席梁繼昌議員同埋其他嘅委員，以及立法會秘書處同埋法律顧問嘅努力，令到二零一七年税務修訂第七四號嘅呢個條例草案嘅審議工作係得以順利完成。我亦都感謝業界對我哋建議嘅税務措施嘅。
條例草案嘅目的係修訂條税務條例，以落實財政司司長喺二零一七一八年度財政預算案裏邊宣佈嘅措施，將利得税豁免嘅範圍擴大至以私人形式發售並且喺香港進行中央管理同埋控制嘅。
二零一六年六月，立法會修訂《證券及期貨條例》，定立開放式基金型公司作為一個基金結構嘅法律框架。透過呢一種新嘅基金嘅結構，我哋希望吸引更多基金嚟嚟係嚟香港註冊，從而提升香港製造基金嘅能力。
但係以私人形式發售嘅在岸基金就需要繳付利得税。鑑於税務待遇不一致，以私人形式發售嘅基金未必會選擇根據新嘅開放式基金型公司嘅制度喺香港註冊。呢個同我哋引入開放式基金型公司結構嘅政策目。
為咗確保可以響税項豁免嘅基金係具有一定嘅規模，能夠推動香港嘅市場發展，以及避免税務措施被濫用，我哋建議以私人形式發售嘅開放式基金型公司需要符合四項條件，先至可以享受呢個利。
反對嘅請舉手。
將應課税嘅收入轉為免税嘅收入。
本會現在成為全體委員會審議。
二零一七年税務修訂第四號條例草案。
我認為議題獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
委員會提係提供税務安排對香港基金業帶嚟嘅好處，同埋適當嘅檢討。誒，代主席，我跟住陳主席。
為咗防止有人被藉著開放式嘅基金型公司嘅結構而避免繳税，我哋會訂立以下措施。第一，
我現在向各位提出嘅待決議題係二零一七年税務修訂第四號條例草案，予以議讀，贊成嘅請舉手。
以及第四，投資基金因提供服務而收取嘅代價或者報酬，不論代價或者報酬係以乜嘢形式嘅發放，都係需要繳付利得税。
同時炒賣或者投機活動。第三，如果居港者持有開放式基金型公司百分之三十或者以上嘅實體嘅實益權益，將需係需要繳付利得税。
第三，公司必須係非集中擁有，以確保公司並非由一小撮嘅投資者持有。否則喺香港進行證券交易並且需要繳交繳付利得税嘅投資者，可以藉著將呢個業務重新包裝成為一個開放式基金型嘅公司，從
為咗照顧實際商業運作需要，開放式基金型公司可以由接受首名投投資者嗰日開始計，有二十四個月嘅時間，已符合非集中擁有嘅條件。我哋亦都會提供一個安全港嘅安排，畀公司可以喺某一啲。
開放式基金型公司不能夠喺香港經營非附表十六A內定明嘅資產類別嘅直接貿易，或者係香港就該等資產經營直接業務嘅實體。呢個係要防止有人以開放式基金型公司嘅結構從事貿易活動，從而
第二開放式基金型公司喺本地同埋海外私人公司嘅投資係可以獲免税，但前提係呢一啲嘅私人公司需要符合某啲關於本地房地產同埋短期資產嘅規定。呢個係為咗防止有人濫用税項豁免而從。
法案委員會曾經討論税務措施會唔會有逃税嘅流動，特別係私人公司有可能喺香港擁有大量資產，因此如果有人透過開放式基金型公司買賣私人公司嘅股份，佢將可以間接噉樣避免就買賣該等香港資產係繳税。
噉我哋喺制定上述嘅防防止避税措施嘅時候，我哋已經考慮到議委員嘅寶貴嘅意見，並且參考最新嘅國際税務標準，以期喺堵塞技術性漏洞同埋推動市場發展嘅需要之間係取得平衡。主席總括而言，條例草。
草案可以為所有開放式基金型公司製造和公平競爭嘅環境，從而吸引更多基金嚟來港註冊，帶動整個基金業服務鏈嘅發展。條例草案同埋各項守後提出嘅修正案已經得到法案委員會嘅支持，我懇請本會誒。
預已通過，畀税務豁免可以一並與開放式基金型公司制度喺今年內落實。我哋亦都留意到，誒議員有提議到，我哋應該係要係有不時檢討呢一個嘅誒法案嘅運作。噉我哋樂意喺適當嘅時候會係向立法會同埋財務誒財經事務。